

Richard Khoo

Contact



+62 82211461294



richard.khoo19@gmail.com



Tanjungpinang, Kepulauan Riau



https://www.linkedin.com/in/catkoo/



https://github.com/Catkoo



https://richard-khoo.vercel.app/

₩ Skills

Programming Languages:

• JavaScript, PHP, HTML, CSS

Backend Development:

 Node.js, Express.js, Firebase (Cloud Integration), RESTful API, MySQL

Frontend & Mobile:

• React Native, Responsive Web Design

Others:

Git, GitHub, Internet of Things (IoT),
 Visual Studio Code

About Me

I am Richard Khoo, a cum laude graduate (GPA 3.70) in Informatics Engineering from Sekolah Tinggi Teknologi Indonesia Tanjung Pinang. I specialize in backend development using Node.js, Express.js, and Firebase. As a Bangkit Academy 2024 (Cloud Computing Path) alumnus, I contributed to a capstone project by integrating backend systems with cloud infrastructure. I have internship experience, enjoy team collaboration, and am passionate about learning new technologies to solve real-world challenges.

Education

Bachelor's degree, Teknik Informatika 2020 - 2024
Sekolah Tinggi Teknologi Indonesia Tanjungpinang
Skill Competencies: Mobile App (React Native), Back-end, Web
Development And Internet Of Thinks, UI / UX Designer

Experience

Bangkit Academy 2024 H1

Febuary 2024 - June 2024

Bangkit Academy led by Google, Tokopedia, Gojek, & Traveloka Completed a 6-month training program led by Google, Tokopedia, Gojek, and Traveloka.

- Collaborated in a team of six to develop the "Tomato Diseases Detection App".
- Focused on backend development and cloud integration using Node.js and Firebase.
- Built and deployed APIs to process and deliver image scan results to the mobile team (React Native).

Intership

March 2023 - December 2023

Ternak Ayam Pak Asun

- Developed a web-based inventory management system to manage goods data efficiently.
- Built and maintained company website using PHP, HTML, CSS, and MySQL.
- Collaborated with stakeholders to improve usability and automate manual processes.